<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <id>https://minetrax.github.io/blog</id>
    <title>MineTrax Suite Blog</title>
    <updated>2023-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
    <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://minetrax.github.io/blog"/>
    <subtitle>MineTrax Suite Blog</subtitle>
    <icon>https://minetrax.github.io/img/favicon.ico</icon>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MineTrax 2.0 has arrived!]]></title>
        <id>https://minetrax.github.io/blog/release-minetrax-v2</id>
        <link href="https://minetrax.github.io/blog/release-minetrax-v2"/>
        <updated>2023-07-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[MineTrax 2.0 has arrived with lot of new features and improvements.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>MineTrax 2.0 has arrived with lot of new features and improvements.</p>
<p>I am thrilled to announce the highly-anticipated release of MineTrax 2.0, a major update that brings an array of exciting features and enhancements to your Minecraft server management experience. Did revamp and refine the entire Admin Section, providing you with an unparalleled level of control and ease of use.
Let's dive into the amazing changes that MineTrax 2.0 has to offer:</p>
<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" alt="AdminDashboard" src="https://minetrax.github.io/assets/images/admindashboard-b9f061c1268bbe94380f44fd14c7d94f.png" width="1907" height="961" class="img_ev3q"></p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="enhanced-admin-section-take-full-control">Enhanced Admin Section: Take Full Control<a href="https://minetrax.github.io/blog/release-minetrax-v2#enhanced-admin-section-take-full-control" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Enhanced Admin Section: Take Full Control" title="Direct link to Enhanced Admin Section: Take Full Control">​</a></h3>
<p>With MineTrax 2.0, managing your Minecraft server is now more seamless than ever before. The Admin Section has been completely overhauled, featuring a streamlined interface and optimized workflow. You will find that handling your server's day-to-day operations is now more intuitive and efficient, putting you firmly in control.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="server-analyticsintel-knowledge-is-power">Server Analytics/Intel: Knowledge is Power<a href="https://minetrax.github.io/blog/release-minetrax-v2#server-analyticsintel-knowledge-is-power" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Server Analytics/Intel: Knowledge is Power" title="Direct link to Server Analytics/Intel: Knowledge is Power">​</a></h3>
<p>Gain valuable insights into your server's performance, player behavior, and resource usage with the newly added Server Analytics/Intel. Armed with this data, you can make informed decisions to optimize your server and ensure a top-notch gaming experience for your players.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="custom-pages-in-new-tab-personalized-experience-easy-navigation">Custom Pages in New Tab: Personalized Experience, Easy Navigation<a href="https://minetrax.github.io/blog/release-minetrax-v2#custom-pages-in-new-tab-personalized-experience-easy-navigation" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Custom Pages in New Tab: Personalized Experience, Easy Navigation" title="Direct link to Custom Pages in New Tab: Personalized Experience, Easy Navigation">​</a></h3>
<p>MineTrax 2.0 introduces a handy option to open Custom Pages in a New Tab, providing your players with a tailored experience while ensuring seamless navigation. Now you can create personalized content for your server and let players explore additional information without losing their place.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="voting-sites-special-url-simplified-voting">Voting Sites Special URL: Simplified Voting<a href="https://minetrax.github.io/blog/release-minetrax-v2#voting-sites-special-url-simplified-voting" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Voting Sites Special URL: Simplified Voting" title="Direct link to Voting Sites Special URL: Simplified Voting">​</a></h3>
<p>We understand the importance of voting for your server, and MineTrax 2.0 makes it even more convenient. With the addition of a Special URL for voting sites, you can direct your players to a single link that redirects them to the voting site of their choice. Simplifying the voting process encourages player engagement and helps your server climb the ranks.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="cookie-consent-for-eu-compliance-meeting-legal-standards">Cookie Consent for EU Compliance: Meeting Legal Standards<a href="https://minetrax.github.io/blog/release-minetrax-v2#cookie-consent-for-eu-compliance-meeting-legal-standards" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Cookie Consent for EU Compliance: Meeting Legal Standards" title="Direct link to Cookie Consent for EU Compliance: Meeting Legal Standards">​</a></h3>
<p>In accordance with EU law, MineTrax 2.0 comes with a built-in Cookie Consent screen, ensuring compliance with regulations. Rest assured, this feature is enabled by default, taking the hassle out of legal compliance and allowing you to focus on what matters most – providing an outstanding gaming experience.</p>
<h3 class="anchor anchorWithHideOnScrollNavbar_WYt5" id="performance-and-stability-improvements">Performance and Stability Improvements<a href="https://minetrax.github.io/blog/release-minetrax-v2#performance-and-stability-improvements" class="hash-link" aria-label="Direct link to Performance and Stability Improvements" title="Direct link to Performance and Stability Improvements">​</a></h3>
<p>To ensure the smoothest experience for you and your players, MineTrax 2.0 comes with upgraded data-tables, complete with search and filter functionalities for all tables. Additionally, the upload size limit for all images has been increased, enabling you to include even higher quality visuals in your server content.</p>
<p>Upgrade to MineTrax 2.0 now and experience the future of Minecraft server management! I sincerely hope that these new features and improvements will elevate your server to new heights and make your Minecraft journey even more enjoyable and successful. Happy gaming!</p>
<p><em>Author: ChatGPT</em></p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Xinecraft</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/xinecraft</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="minetrax" term="minetrax"/>
        <category label="suite" term="suite"/>
        <category label="minecraft" term="minecraft"/>
        <category label="update" term="update"/>
        <category label="release" term="release"/>
        <category label="analytics" term="analytics"/>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title type="html"><![CDATA[MineTrax has arrived!]]></title>
        <id>https://minetrax.github.io/blog/launch</id>
        <link href="https://minetrax.github.io/blog/launch"/>
        <updated>2022-05-20T00:00:00.000Z</updated>
        <summary type="html"><![CDATA[It has been almost a year for me working on MineTrax project.]]></summary>
        <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It has been almost a year for me working on MineTrax project.
I started working on it on my free time with goal to make it some sort of suite for Minecraft survival based servers.</p>
<p>Though it has not completed development I am still releasing it as OSS for anyone interested.</p>
<p>MineTrax is a web suite for Survival based servers. If you are a server owner I recommend you go thru its feature list.
Goal is to make it flexible, you can make it a public facing website or just use it private for analytics purpose.</p>]]></content>
        <author>
            <name>Xinecraft</name>
            <uri>https://github.com/xinecraft</uri>
        </author>
        <category label="launch" term="launch"/>
        <category label="minetrax" term="minetrax"/>
        <category label="suite" term="suite"/>
        <category label="minecraft" term="minecraft"/>
    </entry>
</feed>